Guide to the Methodist Episcopal Church of Lansing, West Dryden and Asburg records,1850-1880.
Methodist Episcopal Church of Lansing, West Dryden and Asburg records,1850-1880
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Methodist Episcopal Church of Lansing, West Dryden and Asburg records, 1850-1880.
6071
Methodist Episcopal Church of Lansing, West Dryden and Asbury (Lansing, N.Y.)
1 reel microfilm.
Microfilm.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Register listing baptisms, marriages, probationers, ministers and members for all three churches (which were charges on one circuit) and class lists for the West Dryden and Asbury societies.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
What is presently called the Lansing United Methodist Church once included Methodist Episcopal charges at North Lansing, West Dryden, Ludlowville and Lansingville. Classes at each of these towns were at one point a circuit whose minister held services at all of their churches. The classes of the Asburg church at Lansing and the Methodist Episcopal church at West Dryden are listed in this register. The Asburg church's class formed in 1797, built its "Red Meeting House" in 1811, and when it burned, built a new church in 1844. The West Dryden Methodist Episcopal class formed in 1811 at what was then known as Fox's Corners, and built its church in 1832. Members of the Lansing Methodist Episcopal church are included in membership lists in the register. During the years 1794-1797 three Methodist classes formed in Lansing, joined in 1797 and built the first frame church in the Genesee circuit.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The register of the Lansing, West Dryden and Asbury churches (1850-1880) lists baptisms, marriages, probationers, ministers, and church and class members. There are several revised lists in most sections, some with dates, but few inclusive dates; that is, many original (not revised) lists of classes and church members have no dates.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Methodist Episcopal Church of Lansing, West Dryden and Asbury (Lansing, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Methodist Episcopal Church.--New York (State)--Lansing.; Church records and registers--New York (State)--Lansing.
Places:
Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Lansing (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; West Dryden (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Asbury (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Minutes.; Baptismal certificates.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Table of contents
  No page numbers.
- Baptisms
  Records date, names, date of birth, administrator/minister, witness.
- Marriages
  Records date, names of parties, residence, place of marriage, minister, witness.
- Probationers
  Records date, name, condition and age, residence, class leader, remarks.
- Probationers, 1853
  Same as above.
- Probationers, revised list, July 13, 1854 and 1855
- Probationers continued, as above.
- Probationers, revised list April 1868.
- Contributions to missionary society for year ending 1877
  Records names and amounts.
- Contributions for same, 1878.
- Contributions for same, 1879.
- Alphabetical list of members, n.d.
  Lists names, residence, time and mode of joining class leader, remarks. Four revised lists follow, with dates and author's signature.
- Class lists for West Dryden and Asbury societies, no dates.
  List class number, title, when meets, names and remarks. Revised lists also appear in this section, some with dates.
- Official members list, n.d.
  Lists local preachers, exhorters, stewards and class leaders.
- Class lists continued, as above.